所以我们讨论了一些相似之处
So we talked about some of the similarities
以及Python之间的一些表面差异
and some of the superficial differences between Python
还有Java。
and Java.
最重要的有意义的区别
The most important meaningful difference
变量n的声明在最上面
is the declaration of that variable n at very top
特别是，它具体做了什么
and in particular, what it does to specify
它的类型和这个词int。
its type with this word int.
那么什么是类型？
So what's a type?
类型是一组可能的值
Well, a type is a set of possible values
以及你的手术
along with the operations that you
可以执行这些值。
can perform on those values.
Java有很多类型。
Java has a number of types.
其中一些是原始类型。
Some of them are primitive types.
这些实际上是由一个小写的单词表示的。
And these are actually indicated by a lowercase word.
所以int是一个表示整数的基元类型。
So int is a primitive type that represents integers.
Long是表示更多整数的基元类型。
Long is a primitive type that represents more integers.
所以int被限制在大约正负20亿。
So int is limited to roughly plus or minus 2 billion.
Long可以表示更大范围的整数。
Long can represent a larger range of integers.
布尔值表示true或false。
Boolean represents either true or false.
Double表示浮点数
Double represents floating point numbers that
里面有小数点。
have a decimal point in them.
Char表示单个字符。
Char represents single characters.
Java也有对象类型。
Java also has object types.
以及在Java中区分原语类型的方式
And the way you distinguish in Java between primitive type
对象类型按惯例大写。
and object type by convention it's capitalized.
所以大写的S字符串表示一系列字符。
So a capital S String represents a sequence of characters.
大写B大整数表示
A capital B Big Integer represents
任意大小的整数。
an integer of arbitrary size.
所以它可以表示相同范围的整数。
So it can represent the same range of integers.
这是一个长扫描。
And it's a long scan.
但它也可以变得和你一样大
But it can also get as big as you
可以保存在程序可用的内存中。
can hold in the memory that's available to your program.
所以从这个意义上说，它就像Python中的一个数字。
So in that sense, it acts like a number in Python.
这些是Java的一些类型，
So those are some of the types that Java has,
尤其是一些价值观
and in particular, some of the values
这些类型可以表示的。
that those types can represent.
但另一个关键特征是
But another key feature of a type
类型具有与其关联的操作。
is that a type has operations associated with it.
操作是接受输入并产生
Operations are functions that take inputs and produce
输出。
outputs.
这些输入和输出就是这些类型的值。
And those inputs and outputs are values of those types.
现在，操作的语法有所不同。
Now, the syntax for operations varies.
一些类型和一些操作内置于语言中。
Some types and some operations are built in to the language.
所以他们使用一种非常熟悉的语法，
And so they use a very familiar syntax,
但是一个非常特殊的，比如中缀标点符号
but a very specialized one like an infix punctuation operator
就像a加b代表操作一样
like a plus b represents the operation
取一个整数a和一个整数b
that takes an integer a and an integer b
并产生一个整数。
and produces an integer.
如果我们要用数学符号来写，
So if we were going to write that in mathematical notation,
我们可以说有一个名为plus的函数
we would say that there is a function named plus that
有两个参数，一个int和一个int，
takes two arguments, an int and an int,
并产生一个int结果。我们知道
and produces an int result. We do
把这当作一个手术，尽管
think of this as an operation even though it's
内置于语言中。
built in to the language.
你会看到另一种手术
Another kind of operation that you'll see
是可以对对象调用的方法。
is a method you can call on an object.
所以当你处理这些大整数时
So when you're working with these big integers, which
是Java提供的任意大小的整数，
are the arbitrary-sized integers that Java offers,
你不能用这个加号运算符。
you can't use this plus operator.
相反，您可以调用该函数
Instead, you invoke that function
通过对要添加的一个整数调用add方法
by calling the add method on one of the integers you want to add
并传入另一个要添加的整数。
and passing in the other integer that you want to add.
但从数学上讲，这实际上是同一种
But mathematically, this is effectively the same kind
作为正数的功能。
of function as plus was.
这个函数，在这个例子中，叫做add，
It's a function that, in this case, is called add,
但这需要一个值和另一个值，
but that takes one value and another value,
它们都是整数，并产生第三个值，
both of them integer-like, and produces a third value,
这是他们的总和。
which is their sum.
这就是表示操作的方法。
So that's the method way of representing an operation.
还有第三种方法，作为函数，
Then there's a third way, which is as a function,
或者，作为一个静态方法，Java会调用它们。
or as a static method is what Java would call them.
例如，如果要使用[？罪恶？]操作，
For example, if you want to use the [? sin ?] operation,
定义在浮点数上，
which is defined on floating point numbers,
那你就打电话给[？数学罪？]而你
then you would call it by calling [? math.sin. ?] And you
会传递一个double，传递值为double，
would pass it a double, pass at a value of double,
记住的是浮点数。
which remember is floating point number.
它将返回一个双倍。
And it will return a double.
它将计算这个三角正弦函数。
And it will compute this trigonometric sine function.
现在，这和我们
Now, this is different than what we
就在这里，因为这个大写的数学是一门课。
did right here because this capital M Math is a class.
它不是物体。
It's not an object.
这是一个碰巧包含sin函数的类。
It's a class that happens to contain the sin function.
所以这唯一的论点
And so the only argument that this takes
这是我们要经过的西塔吗。
is this theta that we're passing in here.
所以这个函数只有一个参数
So this is a function that takes one argument
并产生一个结果。
and produces one result.
所以有各种不同的方法可以对类型进行操作
So there are various different ways that operations on a type
可以用语言表示和显示。
might be represented and shown in the language.
但重要的是要意识到
But the important thing is to realize that underlying it
是某种功能。
is some kind of function.
它可以用不同的方式书写，
And it may be written in different ways,
但基本上还是一样的。
but it's still doing basically the same thing.
例如，在Java中，如果你想
So for example, in Java, if you want
如果要测量一根绳子的长度，你
to take the length of a string, you
对该字符串调用方法。
call a method on that string.
获取要定义长度的字符串
You take the string that you want to define the length
和你做点。后面的length（）以获取
of and you do dot. length() after it in order to get that
方法。
method.
现在，它是一种不同的语法，一种不同的方式
Now, it's a different syntax, a different way
把你想用Python写的东西写成函数，Len，
of writing what you would write in Python as a function, Len,
以字符串作为参数。
that takes the string as an argument.
但基本上是一样的。
But it's fundamentally the same operation.
它是一个输入为字符串的函数
It's a function whose input is a string and whose
输出是字符串长度的整数。
output is the integer that is the length of the string.
只是碰巧使用了不同的语法。
It just happens to use different syntax.
现在，一个麻烦的地方是一些手术，
Now, one troublesome spot is that some operations,
函数的某些名称在某种意义上被重载
some names of functions are overloaded in the sense
相同的操作名用于函数
that the same operation name is used for functions
那需要非常不同的类型。
that take very different types.
在许多编程语言中，您经常看到这一点
You see this frequently in many programming languages
加，减，乘以，
with the arithmetic operators like plus, minus, times,
和分歧。
and divides.
原因是我们对这些很熟悉，
The reason is these are so familiar to us,
数学家已经让它们超载很久了，
and mathematicians have been overloading them for so long,
加号实际上有不同的版本。
that there's actually different versions of plus.
加上我在这里说的，
This plus that I talked about here,
如果a和b有integer类型，它是
if a and b have type integer, it's
将调用整数加法。
going to invoke the integer addition.
但如果a和b有双字型
But if a and b have type double, then it's
将调用双重加法。
going to invoke a double addition.
我们还会在Java中看到一些方法，比如add，
We'll see also in Java that methods, like add,
也可能超载。
can also be overloaded.
几乎所有的编程语言
Almost every programming language
有一定程度的超载。
has some degree of overloading.
可能会有点麻烦。
And it can be a little bit troublesome.
我们一会儿就知道原因了。
And we'll see why in a bit.